Let me show you some images
اسمحوا لي أن أُرِيكم بعض الصّور
of what I consider to be the cities of tomorrow.
لما أعتقد أنها ستكون مدن الغد.
So, that's Kibera, the largest squatter community in Nairobi.
فهذه كيبيرا، أكبر مجتمع عشوائي في نيروبي.
This is the squatter community in Sanjay Gandhi National Park
هذا هو مجتمع العشوائيات في الحديقة الوطنية سانجاي غاندي
in Bombay, India, what's called Mumbai these days.
في بومباي ، بالهند، والتي تسمى مومباي هذه الأيام.
This is Hosinia, the largest and most urbanized favela
هذه هو هوسينيا، أكبر و أكثر الأحياء الفقيرة حضريةً
in Rio de Janeiro.
في ريو دي جانيرو.
And this is Sultanbelyi,
و هذه سلطانبيلي،
which is one of the largest squatter communities in Istanbul.
إحدى كبرى المجتمعات العشوائية في استانبول.
They are what I consider to be the cities of tomorrow,
وتلكم ما أعتقد أنها ستكون مدن الغد،
the new urban world.
العالم الحضري الجديد.
Now, why do I say that?
الآن ، لماذا أقول هذا؟
To tell you about that I have to talk about this fellow here,
لأخبركم عن ذلك عليَّ أن أتحدَّث عن هذا الزميل هنا،
his name is Julius.
اسمه يوليوس.
And I met Julius the last week that I was living in Kibera.
و قد قابلت يوليوس في آخر أسبوع لي مكثته في كيبيرا.
So, I had been there almost three months,
فقد مكثت هناك مدة ثلاثة أشهر تقريبا،
and I was touring around the city going to different squatter areas
و كنت أتجول في المدينة و أذهب لمختلف المناطق العشوائية
and Julius was tagging along, and he was bug eyed
و كان يوليوس يتبعنا ، وقد كان جاحظ العينين
and at certain points we were walking around,
وعند أماكن معينة حيث كنا نتجول،
he grabbed my hand for support,
كان يمسك بيدي للمساعدة.
which is something most Kenyans would never consider doing.
وهو أمر لا يقوم به معظم الكينيين.
They're very polite and they don't get so forward so quickly.
إنهم مهذبون للغاية ولا يقدمون بسرعة على طلب المساعدة.
And I found out later that it was Julius' first day in Nairobi,
وقد علمت لاحقاً أن ذلك كان أول يوم ليوليوس بنيروبي،
and he's one of many.
وهو واحد من الكثير.
So, close to 200,000 people a day
ما يقارب ال ٢٠٠,٠٠٠ شخص في اليوم
migrate from the rural to the urban areas.
يهاجرون من الريف الى المناطق الحضرية.
That's, and I'm going to be fair to the statisticians
وسوف أكون عادلاً مع الإحصائيين
who talked this morning, not almost 1.5 million people a week,
الذين تحدثوا هذا الصباح، ليس ما يقرب من ١,٥ مليون شخص في الأسبوع
but almost 1.4 million people a week but I'm a journalist,
ولكن ما يقرب من ١,٤ مليون شخص في الأسبوع ولكنِّي صحفي ،
and we exaggerate, so almost 1.5 million people a week,
ونحن نبالغ ، لذلك فهي ما يقرب من ١,٥ مليون شخص في الأسبوع،
close to 70 million people a year.
ما يقرب من ٧٠ مليون شخص سنوياً.
And if you do the math, that's 130 people every minute.
و حسابيّاً، يعني ١٣٠ شخص كل دقيقة.
So, that'll be -- in the 18 minutes that I'm given to talk here,
وهكذا ، فسوف يكون ذلك -- في ال ١٨دقيقة التي أعطيت للتحدث هنا
between two and three thousand people will have journeyed to the cities.
ما بين ألفين و ثلاثة آلاف شخص يرحلون للمدن.
And here are the statistics.
وهذه هي الإحصائيات.
Today -- a billion squatters,
اليوم - مليار منطقة عشوائية،
one in six people on the planet.
شخص واحد من بين ستة أشخاص علي كوكب الأرض.
2030 -- two billion squatters,
عام ٢٠٣٠ - ملياران منطقة عشوائية،
one in four people on the planet.
شخصٌ واحدٌ من بين أربع أشخاص على كوكب الأرض.
And the estimate is that in 2050, there'll be three billion squatters,
والتقديرات تقول أنه في عام ٢٠٥٠، سيكون هناك ثلاث مليارات منطقة عشوائية.
better than one in three people on earth.
أكثر من شخص واحد بين ثلاثة أشخاص على الأرض.
So, these are the cities of the future, and we have to engage them.
هذه هي مدن المستقبل ،
And I was thinking this morning of the good life,
وقد كنت أفكر هذا الصباح في الحياة الكريمة،
and before I show you the rest of my presentation,
وقبل أن أعرض عليكم بقية موضوعي هذا،
I'm going to violate TED rules here,
سوف أخالف قواعد تيد،
and I'm going to read you something from my book as quickly as I can.
وسوف أقرأ لكم بعضاً من كتابي هذا بأسرع ما يمكن.
Because I think it says something about reversing our perception
لأنني أعتقد بأنه يتحدث عن تغيير تصورنا
of what we think the good life is.
لما نعتقد أنه الحياة الكريمة.
So -- "The hut was made of corrugated metal, set on a concrete pad.
وقد بني الكوخ من المعدن المموج ، مثبت على قاعدة متينة.
It was a 10 by 10 cell.
عبارة عن حجرة أبعادها ١٠ في ١٠.
Armstrong O'Brian, Jr. shared it with three other men.
يسكنه أرمسترونغ أوبريان الابن مع مشاركة ثلاثة رجال آخرين.
Armstrong and his friends had no water --
أرمسترونغ و أصدقاؤه لم يكن لديهم الماء،
they bought it from a nearby tap owner --
يشترونه من صاحب صنبور مياه بالقرب من سكنهم.
no toilet -- the families in this compound shared a single pit-latrine --
لا توجد مراحيض، تشترك الأسر في هذا المجمع السكني في مرحاض حفرة واحد.
and no sewers or sanitation.
لا توجد مجاري أو صرف صحي.
They did have electricity,
لديهم كهرباء،
but it was illegal service tapped from someone else's wires,
ولكنها كانت خدمة غير قانونية توصل من أسلاك شخص آخر،
and could only power one feeble bulb.
ويمكنها فقط إضاءة مصباح واحد ضعيف.
This was Southland, a small shanty community
كانت هذه ساوثلاند، مجمع أكواخ صغير
on the western side of Nairobi, Kenya.
في الجانب الغربي من نيروبي بكينيا.
But it could've been anywhere in the city,
ولكن من الممكن وجوده في أي مكان بالمدينة،
because more than half the city of Nairobi lives like this.
لأنَّ أكثر من نصف سكان مدينة نيروبي يعيشون هكذا.
1.5 million people stuffed into mud or metal huts
ـ ١,٥مليون شخص يتكدسون داخل أكواخ من الطين والحديد
with no services, no toilets, no rights.
بلا خدمات ، بلا مراحيض ، بلا حقوق.
"Armstrong explained the brutal reality of their situation:
وأوضح أرمسترونغ الواقع الوحشي لوضعهم،
they paid 1,500 shillings in rent, about 20 bucks a month,
إنَّهم يدفعون ١٥٠٠ شلن للإيجار ، ما يعادل ٢٠ دولاراً في الشهر،
a relatively high price for a Kenyan shantytown,
سعرٌ مرتفعٌ نسبياً بالنسبة لمدن الصفيح في كينيا ،
and they could not afford to be late with the money.
ولا يمكنهم تحمُّل التأخُّر في دفع المال.
'In case you owe one month, the landlord will come with his henchmen
'في حال كنت مديناً شهرأً واحداً ، سوف يأتي المالك مع أتباعه
and bundle you out. He will confiscate your things,' Armstrong said.
ويرمون بك خارجاً. وسوف يصادر أشياءك الخاصة ، كما يقول ارمسترونغ.
'Not one month, one day,' his roommate Hilary Kibagendi Onsomu,
" ليس شهراً واحداً، بل يوماً واحداً!" كما تقول هيلاري كبياغندي أونسومو شريكته في السكن،
who was cooking ugali, the spongy white cornmeal concoction
والتي كانت تقوم بطبخ اليوقالي، خلطة اسفنجية من دقيق الذرة الأبيض
that is the staple food in the country, cut into the conversation.
وهي الغذاء الرئيسي للبلد، مقتطعة للحوار.
They called their landlord a Wabenzi, meaning that he is a person
ويسمون الملاك بـ وابينزي، يعني أنه شخص
who has enough money to drive a Mercedes-Benz.
عنده ما يكفي من المال لقيادة سيارة مرسيديس بنز.
Hilary served the ugali with a fry of meat and tomatoes;
قدمت هيلاري اليوقالي مع اللحم والطماطم المقليين،
the sun slammed down on the thin steel roof;
كانت الشمس تضرب بشدة على السقف الحديدي الرقيق،
and we perspired as we ate.
وكنا نتصبب عرقا أثناء الأكل.
"After we finished, Armstrong straightened his tie,
بعد أن فرغنا ، استعدل ارمسترونغ ربطة عنقه،
put on a wool sports jacket, and we headed out into the glare.
ولبس معطف رياضة صوفي، ثم خرجنا في الوهج.
Outside a mound of garbage formed the border
بالخارج تشكل كومة القمامة الحدود
between Southland and the adjacent legal neighborhood of Langata.
بين ساوثلاند وحي لانقاتا القانوني المتاخم.
It was perhaps eight feet tall, 40 feet long, and 10 feet wide.
كانت تقريبا بارتفاع ثمانية أقدام ، بطول ٤٠ قدم ، وبعرض ١٠ أقدام.
And it was set in a wider watery ooze.
وقد وُضِعت في مستنقع طيني عريض.
As we passed, two boys were climbing the mount Kenya of trash.
عند مرورنا كان هناك صبيان يتسلقان "جبل كينيا" للقمامة.
They couldn't have been more than five or six years old.
لم تكن أعمارهما أكثر من خمس أو ست سنوات.
They were barefoot, and with each step their toes sank into the muck
وكانا حافيي القدمين، ومع كل خطوة كانت أصابع أقدامهما تغوص في القمامة
sending hundreds of flies scattering from the rancid pile.
باعثةً مئات الذباب وقد تناثر من الكومة النتنة.
I thought they might be playing King of the Hill, but I was wrong.
اعتقدت أنهم يلعبون لعبة ملك الجبل، ولكني كنت مخطئاً.
Once atop the pile, one of the boys lowered his shorts,
وعند قمة الكومة ، خفض أحد الولدين سرواله ،
squatted, and defecated.
جلس القرفصاء ، ثم تغوط.
The flies buzzed hungrily around his legs.
حلَّق الذباب جائعاً حول ساقيه.
When 20 families -- 100 people or so -- share a single latrine,
عندما تشترك ٢٠ أسرة - ما يقارب ١٠٠ شخص- مرحاضاً واحداً،
a boy pooping on a garbage pile is perhaps no big thing.
فإن تغوُّطَ صبيٍّ على كومة قمامة قد لا يعني شيئاً كبيراً.
But it stood in jarring contrast
ولكنْ على النقيض تماماً
to something Armstrong had said as we were eating --
من ما ذكره ارمسترونغ أثناء تناولنا للطعام-
that he treasured the quality of life in his neighborhood.
أنه يقدِّر مستوى الحياة في مجاورته.
"For Armstrong, Southland wasn't constrained by its material conditions.
بالنسبة لارمسترونغ، فان ساوثلاند غير مقيدة بحالتها الماديّة.
Instead, the human spirit radiated out
بدلاً عن ذلك، فإنَّ روح الإنسان تشعُّ منبعثةً
from the metal walls and garbage heaps to offer something
من الحوائط المعدنية و أكوام القمامة لتقدم شيئاً
no legal neighborhood could: freedom.
لا تقدمه أي مجاورة قانونية - الحرية.
'This place is very addictive,' he had said.
ثم قال" قد تدمن هذا المكان بدرجة كبيرة،".
'It's a simple life, but nobody is restricting you.
"إنها حياة بسيطة، ولكن لا أحد يفرض عليك قيود
Nobody is controlling what you do.
ولا أحد يحكم ما تفعل
Once you have stayed here, you cannot go back.'
حالما مكثت هنا، لا يمكنك العودة."
He meant back beyond that mountain of trash,
وقصد بالعودة، إلى ما وراء جبال القمامة،
back in the legal city, of legal buildings,
العودة للمدن القانونية، ذات المباني القانونية،
with legal leases and legal rights.
بعقود الإيجار القانونية والحقوق القانونية.
'Once you have stayed here,' he said,
وقال "حالما مكثت هنا،"
'you can stay for the rest of your life.'"
يمكنك البقاء ما تبقى لك من الحياة."
So, he has hope, and this is where these communities start.
لذا فهو لديه أمل، ومن هنا تبدأ هذه المجتمعات.
This is perhaps the most primitive shanty that you can find in Kibera,
ربما يكون هذا الكوخ هو الأكثر بدائية في كيبيرا،
little more than a stick-and-mud hut next to a garbage heap.
أصغر بقليل من كوخ القش والطين القريب من كومة القمامة.
This is getting ready for the monsoon in Bombay, India.
هذا هو الاستعداد لرياح المنسون في بومباي بالهند.
This is home improvement:
هذا هو تحسين المنزل.
putting plastic tarps on your roof.
وضع الأقمشة البلاستيكية على السطح.
This is in Rio de Janeiro, and it's getting a bit better, right?
وهذا في ريو دي جانيرو، هذه أفضل حالاً، أليس كذلك؟
We're seeing scavenged terra cotta tile and little pieces of signs,
فنرى بلاط تيراكوتا المنظَّف وقطع قليلة من اللافتات،
and plaster over the brick, some color,
والجص على الطوب، بعض الألوان،
and this is Sulay Montakaya's house in Sultanbelyi, and it's getting even better.
وهذا منزل سولي مونتاكايا في سلطانبيلي، وهذا أيضا أحسن حالاً.
He's got a fence; he scavenged a door;
به سياج،
he's got new tile on the roof.
لديه بلاط جديد على السطح.
And then you get Rocinha
ثم لديكم هنا روسينها
and you can see that it's getting even better.
ويمكنك أن ترى أنّه أفضل حالاً.
The buildings here are multi-story.
كل المباني هنا متعددة الطوابق.
They develop -- you can see on the far right
وقد بنوا-- يمكنك أن ترى في أقصى اليمين
one where it seems to just stack on top of each other,
حيث يبدو أبنيةً مكومةً فوق بعضها البعض،
room, after room, after room.
غرفة بعد غرفة بعد غرفة.
And what people do is they develop their home on one or two stories,
وما يفعله الناس هو أنهم يبنون منازلهم من طابق أو طابقين،
and they sell their loggia or roof rights,
ثم يبيعون ملكية اللوجيا أو السطح،
and someone else builds on top of their building,
ثم يبني شخص آخر فوق مبناهم،
and then that person sells the roof rights,
ثم يبيع ذلك الشخص ملكية السطح،
and someone else builds on top of their building.
ثم يبني شخص آخر فوق مبناهم.
All of these buildings are made out of reinforced concrete and brick.
كل تلك المباني مصنوعة من الخرسانة المسلحة والطوب.
And then you get Sultanbelyi, in Turkey, where it's even built
ثم هنا نجد سلطانبيلي بتركيا حيث بنيت
to a higher level of design.
بمستوى عال من التصميم .
The crud in the front is mattress stuffing,
هذا المتناثر بالأمام هو عبارة عن حشو مرتبة،
and you see that all over Turkey.
ونرى ذلك في كل أرجاء تركيا.
People dry out or air out their mattress stuffing on their roofs.
فالناس يجففون أو يعرضون مراتبهم للهواء على سطوح منازلهم.
But the green building, on behind,
أمّا المبنى "ذا العمارة المستدامة" ، في الخلف،
you can see that the top floor is not occupied,
فبإمكانك أن ترى أن الطابق العلوي غير مأهول بالسكان،
so people are building with the possibility of expansion.
فعند البناء يضع الناس التوسع في حسبانهم .
And it's built to a pretty high standard of design.
والذي بُنِيَ على مستوً عالٍ جداً من التصميم.
And then you finally get squatter homes like this,
ثم أخيرا لدينا منازل عشوائية كهذه،
which is built on the suburban model.
وهي مبنية على طراز الضواحي.
Hey, that's a single family home in the squatter community.
مهلاً، هذا منزل لأسرة واحدة في المجتمع العشوائي.
That's also in Istanbul, Turkey.
وهو أيضا في استانبول بتركيا.
They're quite vital places, these communities.
فهذه المجتمعات أماكن حيوية جداً ، .
This is the main drag of Rocinha, the Estrada da Gavea,
هذا هو الجرار الرئيسي في روسينها ، استرادا دا قافيا،
and there's a bus route that runs through it,
وهناك طريق للحافلة يمرُّ عبرها،
lots of people out on the street.
الكثير من الناس في الشارع.
These communities in these cities are actually more vital
هذه المجتمعات في هذه المدن في حقيقة الأمر أكثر حيويةً
than the illegal communities.
من تلك المجتمعات غير القانونية.
They have more things going on in them.
لديهم أشياء أكثر تحدث لهم.
This is a typical pathway in Rocinha called a "beco" --
هذا هو المسار النموذجي في روسينها ويسمى بيكو--
these are how you get around the community.
وعبرها يمكنك التجوال حول المُجَمَّع.
It's on very steep ground.
إنّه على أرض منحدرة جداً.
They're built on the hills, inland from the beaches in Rio,
فهي مبنية على التلال ، نحو الداخل من الشواطئ في ريو،
and you can see that the houses are just cantilevered over the natural obstructions.
ويمكنك أن ترى أن المنازل ناتئة مباشرة من فوق العقبات الطبيعية.
So, that's just a rock in the hillside.
فهذا مجرد صخرة صغيرة على جانب التل.
And these becos are normally very crowded,
وتلك الـ بيكو تكون عادة مزدحمة جدا،
and people hump furniture up them, or refrigerators up them,
فالناس يجمعون الأثاثات أو الثلاجات بالقمة،
all sorts of things.
كل أنواع الأشياء.
Beer is all carried in on your shoulders.
والبيرة هي كل ما تحمله على أكتافك.
Beer is a very important thing in Brazil.
فالبيرة شئ مهم جدا في البرازيل.
This is commerce in Kenya, right along the train tracks,
هذه هي المناطق التجارية في كينيا ، ممتدة على طول مسار القطار،
so close to the train tracks that the merchants
قريبةٌ جداً من مسار القطار لدرجة أنَّ الباعة
sometimes have to pull the merchandise out of the way.
في بعض الأحيان عليهم أن يسحبوا البضائع بعيداً عن الطريق.
This is a marketplace, also in Kenya, Toi Market,
هذا سوق ، أيضا في كينيا، سوق توي،
lots of dealers, in almost everything you want to buy.
الكثير من التجار ، يوجد كل شيء تقريبا تريد شراؤه.
Those green things in the foreground are mangoes.
تلك الأشياء الخضراء في المقدمة هي عبارة عن مانجو.
This is a shopping street in Kibera,
هذا شارع تسوق في كيبيرا،
and you can see that there's a soda dealer, a health clinic,
ويمكنك أن ترى أن هناك بائع مياه غازية، وعيادة صحية،
two beauty salons, a bar, two grocery stores, and a church, and more.
صالونين للتجميل ، حانة، بقالتين، وكنيسة ، والكثير.
It's a typical downtown street; it just happens to be self-built.
إنه شارع نموذجي في وسط المدينة ، وقد حدث أنْ تكوَّن بالبناء الذاتي.
This here, on the right-hand side,
وههنا ، على الجانب الأيمن،
is what's called a -- if you look at the fine print under the awning --
ما يسمى -- اذا نظرت الى الكتابة الدقيقة تحت المظلة--
it's a hotel.
انه فندق.
And what hotel means, in Kenya and India, is an eating-place.
وما يقصد بالفندق ، في كينيا والهند، هو مكان لتناول الطعام.
So, that's a restaurant.
فذلك مطعم.
People steal electrical power -- this is Rio.
يسرق الناس الطاقة الكهربائية-- هذه ريو.
People tap in and they have thieves who are called "grillos" or "crickets,"
الناس يوصلون الكهرباء ولديهم لصوص يدعون الجراد أو الصراصير،
and they steal the electrical power
ويسرقون الطاقة الكهربائية،
and wire the neighborhood.
ثم يغذون المجاورة السكنية.
People burn trash to get rid of the garbage,
يحرق الناس القمامة كي يتخلصوا من الأوساخ.
and they dig their own sewer channels.
ويحفرون قنوات الصرف الصحي بأنفسهم.
Talk about more plastic bags than plankton.
وحدِّثْ عن أكياس البلاستيك الأكثر من العوالق.
And sometimes they have natural trash-disposal.
وفي بعض الأحيان لديهم معالجة نفايات طبيعية.
And when they have more money they cement their streets,
وعندما يكون لديهم المزيد من المال فانهم يرصفون الشوارع.
and they put in sewers and good water pipes, and stuff like that.
ويحفرون مجاري الصرف الصحي وأنابيب مياه الشرب وأشياء من هذا القبيل.
This is water going to Rio. People run their water pipes all over the place,
هذا ماء ذاهب الى ريو، والناس يمررون أنابيب المياه في كل مكان ،
and that little hut right there has a pump in it, and that's what people do:
وذلك الكوخ الصغير هناك به مضخة، وهذا ما يفعله الناس.
they steal electricity; they install a pump
يسرقون الكهرباء ، ثم يركبون المضخة
and they tap into the water main, and pump water up to their houses.
ثم يوصلونها مع أنبوب الماء الرئيسي، ويضخون الماء الى منازلهم.
So, the question is how do you go from the mud-hut village,
لذا ، فالسؤال هو كيف يمكنك أن تذهب من قرية كوخ الطين ،
to the more developed city, to the even highly developed Sultanbelyi?
للمدينة الأكثر تطوراً، إلى سلطانبيلي التي هي على مستوً عالٍ من التطور؟
I say there are two things.
أنا أقول هناك شيئان اثنان.
One is people need a guarantee they won't be evicted.
الأول هو أن الناس بحاجة الى أن يضمنوا بأنهم لن يطردوا.
That does not necessarily mean property rights,
هذا لا يعني بالضرورة حقوق الملكية ،
and I would disagree with Hernando de Soto on that question,
فأنا أختلف مع هيرناندو دي سوتو على هذا السؤال،
because property rights create a lot of complications.
لأن حقوق الملكية تخلق الكثير من التعقيدات،
They're most often sold to people, and people then wind up in debt
فهي في معظم الأحيان تباع للناس، ثم ينتهون بالديون
and have to pay back the debt,
وعليهم تسديد الديون
and sometimes have to sell their property
وفي بعض الأحيان عليهم بيع ممتلكاتهم
in order to pay back the debt.
كي يستطيعوا تسديد الديون.
There's a whole variety of other reasons why property rights
هناك مجموعة متنوعة من الأسباب الأخرى توضح أن حقوق الملكية
sometimes don't work in these cases,
في بعض الأحيان لا تنجح في هذه الحالات،
but they do need security of tenure.
لكنهم يحتاجون الى أمن الحيازة.
And they need access to politics, and that can mean two things.
وهم يحتاجون إلى الوصول إلى السياسيين ، وذلك قد يعني شيئين.
That can mean community organizing from below,
قد يعني ذلك تنظيم المجتمع من الأسفل،
but it can also mean possibilities from above.
ولكن قد يعني أيضا الإمكانيات من الأعلى.
And I say that because the system in Turkey is notable.
وأقول ذلك لأن النظام في تركيا مرموق.
Turkey has two great laws that protect squatters.
تركيا لديها قانونان يحميان المجتمعات العشوائية.
One is that -- it's called "gecekondu" in Turkish,
الأول وهو-- يسمى جيسيكوندو بالتركية،
which means "built overnight," and if you build your house overnight
وهو ما يعني بين عشية وضحاها ، فإذا بنيت منزلك في ليلة واحدة
in Turkey, you can't be evicted without due process of law,
في تركيا، لا يمكن أن تطرد دون اتباع الإجراءات القانونية اللازمة ،
if they don't catch you during the night.
اذا لم يمسك بك أحد أثناء الليل.
And the second aspect is that once you have 2,000 people
والجانب الثاني هو أنه بمجرد أن يكون لديك ٢٠٠٠ شخص
in the community, you can petition the government
في المجتمع، يمكنك مطالبة الحكومة
to be recognized as a legal sub-municipality.
بأن تكون معترف بك كبلدية فرعية شرعية.
And when you're a legal sub-municipality, you suddenly have politics.
وعندما تكون بلدية فرعية شرعية ، فجأة يكون لديك سياسيين.
You're allowed to have an elected government, collect taxes,
ويسمح لك بأن يكون لديك حكومة منتخبة، تجمع الضرائب،
provide municipal services, and that's exactly what they do.
وتوفر خدمات البلدية ، وهذا هو بالضبط ما يفعلونه.
So, these are the civic leaders of the future.
فهؤلاء هم قادة المستقبل المدنيون.
The woman in the center is Geeta Jiwa.
السيدة في الوسط هي جيتا جيوا.
She lives in one of those tents on the highway median in Mumbai.
تسكن في إحدى تلك الخيام في منتصف الطريق السريع في مومباي.
That's Sureka Gundi; she also lives with her family
وهذه سوريكا قوندي، وهي أيضا تسكن مع أسرتها
on the tent along the same highway median.
في الخيمة بمحاذاة نفس وسط الطريق السريع.
They're very outspoken. They're very active.
إنهم صريحون جداً. و نشطون للغاية.
They can be community leaders.
يمكن أن يكونوا قادة مجتمع.
This woman is Nine, which means "grandma" in Turkish.
هذه السيدة هي نيني، والتي تعني جدة بالتركية.
And there were three old ladies who lived in --
وكانت هناك ثلاث سيدات متقدمات في السن يسكنَّ في --
that's her self-built house behind her -- and they've lived there for 30 or 40 years,
ذلك هو منزلها ذاتي البناء من خلفها-- وقد سكنَّ فيه لمدة ٣٠ أو ٤٠ عاماً،
and they are the backbone of the community there.
وهنَّ العمود الفقري للمجتمع هناك.
This is Richard Muthama Peter,
وهذا هو ريتشارد موثاما بيتر،
and he is an itinerant street photographer in Kibera.
وهو مصوِّر فوتوغرافي متجوِّل في كيبيرا.
He makes money taking pictures of the neighborhood,
انه يكسب المال بالتقاط صور للمجاورة السكنية ،
and the people in the neighborhood,
وسكان المجاورة
and is a great resource in the community.
ويعد مصدراً عظيماً للمجتمع.
And finally my choice to run for mayor of Rio is Cezinio,
وأخيراً خياري في الترشح كعمدة ريو هو سيزينيو،
the fruit merchant with his two kids here,
بائع الفواكهه مع طفليه الاثنين،
and a more honest and giving and caring man I don't know.
ولا أعرف رجلاً أكثر أمانة وعطاء ورعاية مثله.
The future of these communities is in the people
مستقبل تلك المدن في الناس
and in our ability to work with those people.
وفي مقدرتنا على العمل مع أولئك الناس.
So, I think the message I take, from what I read from the book,
لذا، أعتقد أن الرسالة التي أستخلصها، مما قرأته من الكتاب،
from what Armstrong said, and from all these people,
مما قاله آرمسترونج، ومن كل أولئك الناس،
is that these are neighborhoods.
هي أن هذه مجاورات سكنية.
The issue is not urban poverty.
المسألة ليست فقر المناطق الحضرية.
The issue is not the larger, over-arching thing.
والقضية ليست هي الشئ الأكبر المهيمن.
The issue is for us to recognize that these are neighborhoods --
المسألة بالنسبة لنا أن نعترف بأن هذه هي مجاورات سكنية.
this is a legitimate form of urban development --
هذا شكل شرعي للتنمية الحضرية ،
and that cities have to engage these residents,
ويجب على المدن إشراك هؤلاء السكان ،
because they are building the cities of the future.
لأنهم يقومون ببناء مدن المستقبل.
Thank you very much.
شكراً جزيلاً.